Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/tarrysingh (LinkedIn) tarrysingh.com (Personal) github.com/tarrysingh (Other) deepkapha.ai (Company)

Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence
Deep Learning
Strategy

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Dutch (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Elementary)

Certifications

Growth Hacking Fundamentals Mobile Marketing Fundamentals Growth Hacking Fundamentals

Honors-Awards
VMware VExpert

Publications

Solvency II - Enterprise informatie management noodzaak voor Europese verzekeraars

Smart Metering the Clouds

Oracle Private Cloud

Can Virtualization threaten security and compliance?

7 steps to virtual server protection

Tarry Singh

CoFounder & Principal Al Instructor at LiveAl, also Founder deepkapha.ai, curae.ai & Real Al

Greater Groningen Area

Summary

Follow Tarry on

Twitter: twitter.com/tarrysingh

Instagram : Instagram.com/tarrysingh

Blog: https://tarrysingh.com

GitHub: https://github.com/tarrysingh

Experienced, entrepreneurial and a well rounded data obsessed professional with over 20 years experience in multiple industries.

Dutch national with deep multicultural experience having worked with 40+ nationalities in U.S, Brazil, Singapore, #China, #Japan and Europe.

Entrepreneur and SME with deep industry knowledge in deep learning, machine learning and artificial intelligence. Internationally acknowledged speaker, author, mentor and startup coach.

An organizationally sensitive advisor with deep understanding of both subjective and objective challenges within the organization; I thrive relentlessly to help improve the individual and organizational performance of my clients by supporting in transformational change management programs in IT strategy, innovation, AI, digital & data analytics transformation.

I am genuinely interested in my coworkers as well as my "C-level" relationships and I strive relentlessly to create a real and empathic case for change: with right team and for lasting impact.

I have (co-)authored several research publications and books – in research (ieee, ACM etc)as well as practical industry areas. Also proud to work with various humanitarian & NGOs like UN etc to help build the broken world with technology.

Highlighted domain expertise in:

- 1. Al & Data Skills: Digital & Data Analytics Transformation with Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence
- 2. Innovation & Startup Growth: Advising Enterprises, startups and VC/PEs

Experience

LiveAl

CoFounder & Principal AI Instructor July 2020 - Present (2 months)

Amsterdam, North Holland, Netherlands

LiveAl is a European EdTech program co-founded by Tarry Singh and Ms. Foke Van Der Helm with a vision to share and multiply knowledge for people that want to gain highly demanded skills through live online courses.

LiveAI is created to accommodate the fast growing demand for our training, generated through

the immense global community support. It started out as an experiment in 2017, with workshops and applied various blended learning models on location to more than 27.500 learners so far.

What they discovered is that the real intrinsic process of "learning by doing" can only happen

when the following factors are in place: 1) hands-on learning from real world Al projects, 2) mentored by

seasoned industry professionals and 3) career guidance through experience.

All instructors at LiveAl have been hand-picked to train their learners through mastery of in-demand skills. LiveAl offers aspiring participants globally, the opportunity to participate in some of the most exciting and innovative markets in the world.

deepkapha.ai Founder and Al Researcher January 2018 - Present (2 years 8 months) Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

deepkapha.ai is an entrepreneurial research lab that wants to solve worlds hunger for really hard problems with AI (that's with ML & DL)

We work with both Executive Board of Global companies as well as Engineers/ Managers/Architects step by step in the inner workings of Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence.

With our "Applied Al" program, we then develop groundbreaking artificial intelligence solutions and algorithms with deep learning for them.

Industries focus => Healthcare, Automotives, Manufacturing, Internet, Retail, Telecom and Services.

How we do this?

We have three arms namely, Enterprise Al Engineering, Al Research and Philanthropy.

#1 Al Solutions :: Goal is also to bridge the talent and innovation gap by helping corporate board , Chair(wo)men, CEO of both enterprises as well as startups/scale-ups with tangible & ROI driven deep learning projects.

#2 AI Research:: Through #DeepRRP (remote residency program), we are working with world's upcoming and top researchers (PhD, Post Docs), computer scientists and enthusiasts.

#3 Philanthropy:: Philanthropy is a deep passion and desire of Tarry to level the playing field and bring machine learning and deep learning to anyone and everyone. We work with humanitarian and non-profit organizations like United Nations / Hult Prize Foundation, Re:coded in Turkey, Iraq, Syria and more.

Who's behind deepkapha.ai?

Tarry is CEO, Founder of deepkapha.ai. He is a seasoned entrepreneur, tech professional, author & neuroscience researcher and acknowledged public speaker in Innovation fireside chats & AI/ML/Electric Vehicle, Conputational Biology / HealthTech, Autonomous Transportation keynotes.

He's interviewed regularly by the media Al-Jazeera, Associated Press etc. and features on international TV to push the tech agenda for enhancement of the human race.

curae.ai
Cofounder & CEO [Stealth]
August 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month)
Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

curae.ai (pronounced "kooraaey-dot-ai') is an Al Healthcare Startup Project - brought to you by \mathbb{R} eal Al Inc.

An initiative born out of deepkapha.ai solutions (https://deepkapha.ai/ai-solutions/) basket

Its mission is to serve healthcare professionals, hospitals and health seekers with an AI platform that will enable them to do their jobs faster while reducing their costs dramatically.

Our product development is in progress and we will soon announce a private beta testing for select healthcare institutions, hospitals and healthcare- and Al professionals.

World Health Organization
Founding Member Focus Group Al4H
March 2020 - Present (6 months)
Europe

Over the past decade, considerable resources have been allocated to exploring the use of AI for health, which has revealed an immense potential. Yet, due to the complexity of AI models, it is difficult to understand their strengths, weaknesses, and limitations. If the technology is poorly designed or the underlying training data are biased or incomplete, errors or problematic results can occur. AI technology can only be used with complete confidence if it has been quality controlled through a rigorous evaluation in a standardized way. Towards developing this standard assessment framework of AI for health, the ITU has established FG-AI4H in partnership with the WHO.

Thus far, FG-Al4H has established several topic groups, including Al and cardiovascular disease risk prediction, child growth monitoring, dermatology, falls among the elderly, histopathology, neuro-cognitive diseases, ophthalmology (retinal imaging diagnostics), psychiatry, radiotherapy, snakebite and snake identification, symptom assessment, tuberculosis, volumetric chest computed tomography, and dental diagnostics and digital dentistry.

The University of Texas at Dallas Visiting Faculty — AI, Machine Learning, Deep Learning May 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Dallas, Texas

In collaboration with CS department, I and my TAs deliver hard-core machine learning & deep learning bootcamps, conduct hackathons and teach students compressed yet focused industry relevant AI tools & techniques.

This helps us to focus on developing talent, fostering innovation with companies and talent placements (within deepkapha.ai and other leading global companies focused on ML, DL & Al in our client network)

Forbes

Contributing Editor -- Artificial Intelligence and its Impact on Business & Society

September 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Global

Writing for CognitiveWorld.com Forbes Site about AI and its impact on society and businesses. I will write frequently about applied AI in business domains, future of employment, career development and more relevant topics for the Forbes audience.

PA Consulting

Managing Consultant Digital & Data Analytics August 2014 - 2017 (3 years)

Amsterdam & London

Advisor and Trusted Client Partner to CxOs [CEO, CFO, CIO and CDO] of Global Blue Chip Clients on Digital & Data Analytics Transformation by uniquely deploying lean start-up methods. These methods developed from real-world startup experience such as Growth Multipliers — from envisioning "Book of Dreams" with client teams TO "Digital & Data Analytics Playbook" of Realistic Pilots with tangible multipliers.

Focus areas:

- Digital Transformation (Cloud , Data Analytics, Machine learning & Artificial Intelligence)
- Big Data, M2M & Internet of Things (IoT)
- IT Sourcing (Hardware, Software, Services)
- IT & Corporate Strategy: Org Design, Setup & Scale

0&1

CEO / Managing Partner
July 2012 - July 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Social Networking, Collaboration & Analytics SaaS Startup. Helped reorganise (from traditional services to product and cloud services), restructure and developed an enterprise social networking platform for both enterprise and SMB market. Platform specs: Built on SharePoint / Azure Cloud & deployed within SaaS, PaaS & laaS models.

QS Advisory
Vice President
August 2010 - July 2014 (4 years)
London, United Kingdom

Management Consulting Startup focused on creating a Global Sourcing Ecosystem in Continental Europe. Enabled F500 clients to implement complex outsourcing initiatives to bring about transformation by achieving sustained cost savings and improved productivity. Total value of technology deals >€ 2Bn where client IT spend ranging from €200M - €2Bn with revenues ranging between ranging between €5 Bn- €120 Bn.

Atos Consulting
Executive Business Consultant
January 2008 - August 2010 (2 years 8 months)
Utrecht Area, Netherlands

Head of Data, Virt & Infrastructure

Win & Deliver to CxO with special focus on SaaS, PaaS & IaaS solutions pertaining to IT Sourcing, Digital / Data Analytics, Infrastructure & Data Center (On-prem, Hybrid and Cloud Computing). Key roles and responsibilities in EMEA/APAC: Trusted advisor to C-level executives, Business Development, Technology Leadership, Project Management & Delivery for various infrastructure transition & transformation programs.

Hanzehogeschool Groningen / Hanze University of Applied Sciences Groningen Head of Data, Middleware & Infrastructure January 2003 - December 2007 (5 years) Groningen Area, Netherlands - Head of Middleware & Data Team. Sourcing and supplier management & International project for NUFFIC in Uganda (technology projects in virtualization and data center technologies)

Royal Wagenborg Head of Data | Project Manager & Oracle DBA 2000 - 2003 (3 years)

Responsible for operational lead an

Groningen Area, Netherlands

Responsible for operational lead and product development & management for an in-house mission critical EDI application (Inventory, Purchase and Maintenance for onboard vessels and offshore global installations). Managed project worth € 12 M.

Establish an in-house training & coaching for maintenance & procurement program

Supplier and sourcing expertise

Database and applications management

Project & program management

Education

Columbia University in the City of New York

MicroMasters Program (Completing eventually with Ph.D program here or
elsewhere), Artificial Intelligence · (2017 - 2021)

University of Mumbai

Post Master / Dphil equiv @L.B.S College of Advanced Maritime Studies and Research, Nautical Sciences / Astronomy · (1991 - 1995)

Delhi University

Bachelor's degree, Physics · (1987 - 1991)

Kendriya Vidyalaya

High School, VWO · (1985 - 1987)